Finding Aid for James Fairbairn Smith papers, 1924 and 1945-1975
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
James Fairbairn Smith papers 1924, 1945-1975
Smith, James Fairbairn.
2 linear feet
85375 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of James Fairbairn Smith (donor no. 5401 ) and came to the library in 1976.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
James Fairbairn Smith was editor-in-chief of Masonic World and a writer on the history of masonry.
The James Fairbairn Smith collection include correspondence, research files, and manuscripts of his writings.
Subjects:
Freemasonry.; Journalists--United States.; Smith, James Fairbairn.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bay City (Mich.); Bonisteel, Roscoe O. (Roscoe Osmond), b. 1888.; Freemasonry.; Fraternal organizations.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Masonic philanthropy
  - Michigan Masonic Home and Hospital Alma, Michigan, 11 folders (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Manuscript: The Rise of the Ecossais Degrees by J. Fairbairn Smith (Box 1)
  - Manuscript: 150 Epic Years: Detroit Lodge No. 2 by J. Fairbairn Smith (preliminary copy) (Box 1)
  - Writings by James Fairbairn Smith (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1945 (Box 1)
  - 1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948 (Box 1)
  - 1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950 (Box 1)
  - 1951 (Box 1)
  - 1952 (Box 1)
  - 1953 (Box 1)
  - 1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 2)
  - 1961 (Box 2)
  - 1962 (Box 2)
  - 1963 (Box 2)
  - 1964 (Box 2)
  - 1965 (Box 2)
  - 1966 (Box 2)
  - 1967 (Box 2)
  - 1968 (Box 2)
  - 1969 (Box 2)
  - 1970 (Box 2)
  - 1971 (Box 2)
  - 1972 (Box 2)
  - 1973 (Box 2)
  - 1974 (Box 2)
  - 1975 (Box 2)
- Masonic History
  - Reports of the Masonic History Committee (Box 2)
  - R.S. Lindsay--Historical Research and Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Historical research
    - Stephen Morin (Box 2)
    - Henry Andrew Francken (Box 2)
    - Mirabeau (Box 2)
    - Constitutions of 1762 and 1786 (Box 2)
    - Rose Croix (Box 2)
    - Prevost; Shirreff (Box 2)
    - MacMahon family; Rite of Seven Degrees (Box 2)
    - The Masonic Order in the West Indies (Box 2)
    - Ferrers (Box 2)
    - Freemasonry in France (Box 2)
    - Choumitzky (Box 2)
    - Frederick the Great (Box 2)
    - The Masonic Order in France (Box 2)
  - Historical Documents--Sharpe Collection (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Photographs of the officers of the Bay City (Mich.) Temple, 1924 (Box 2)